Inventory of the Kenneth Kantor papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Kenneth Kantor papers
1937-1975
2012C24
Hoover Institution Archives
4 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box (2.2 linear feet)
Contains printed newspaper writings, drafts of articles, letters, and photographs relating to the post-World War II American occupation of Japan, the Korean War, and other subjects.
Kantor, Kenneth.
Access
The collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2012.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Born on January 22, 1920, Kenneth Dwight Kantor was an American journalist who spent most of his career in Japan and Korea. He covered post-World War II Japan and the war in Korea, including subjects such as the status of women’s rights in Japan and refugees in Korea. He worked for the National Broadcast Company. In 1948, he married Margaret (Marjorie) A. Crook, who had also worked for the Far East Command.
Scope and Content of Collection
Contains printed newspaper writings, drafts of articles, letters, and photographs relating to the post-World War II American occupation of Japan, the Korean War, and other subjects.
Japan--History--Allied occupation, 1945-1952.; Journalists.; Korean War, 1950-1953.
- Byline articles, 1949-1964 (Box-folder 1: 1)
- Correspondence to the National Broadcasting Company (United States) and public relations, 1944-1975 (Box-folder 1: 2)
- National Broadcasting Company (NBC), "News on the Far East,", 1950-1951 (Box-folder 1: 3)
- Professional references and recommendations, 1947-1965 (Box-folder 1: 4)
- Article drafts, 1947-1950 (Box-folder 1: 5)
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes:
  "Japan's Nurses are Becoming Professional RN's"
  "The Story That Could Not Be Told"
  "Jet Ride To Danger" in Saga: The Magazine of True Adventure, March 1951
  "Hiroshima Hero" (plus alternate titles), "I Bummed A Jet Ride to Korea"
  "American Sailor on Horseback Upsets Japanese in Ancient Sport"
  "Kimono Revolt!"
  "Cultured Pearls to Be Available in Large Quantities"
  "Anomaly on Wheels"
  "...On Our Children and Our Children's Children"
  "Mama-San's Kids"
  "Oil Horizon's Expanding in Volcanic Japan"
  "China's Natural Gas May Be the Answer to Tokyo's Shortage"
  "Oil for a New Japan"
  "Pipe Line or Pipe Dream?"
  "Big Blow"
  "Tokyo's Water System"
  "New York to Los Angeles in 288 Diapers!"
- "What Is America Thinking?," article, undated (Box-folder 1: 6)
- Writings, clippings, and correspondence from Kantor's time in Japan, 1947-1950 (Box-folder 1: 7-8)
- Articles by Kenneth Kantor for Lurton Blassingame, undated
  - "I Hunted the World's Biggest Animal" by William M. Terry, as told to Ken Kantor (Box-folder 1: 9)
  - "Nightmare Above the World" or "Nightmare 10,000 Feet Up" by Lt. Hugh Casey, as told to Ken Kantor (Box-folder 1: 10)
  - "The Story That Could Not Be Told" (Box-folder 1: 11)
  - "Can the Communists Take Japan?" (Box-folder 1: 12)
  - "Kimono Revolt" article and accompanying photographs (Box-folder 1: 13)
- "Photographic Picture Book of Nikko, National Park of Japan," dedicated to Marjorie Kantor, 1948 (Box-folder 2: 1)
- Photograph album depicting kimonos and Buddha statues, undated (Box-folder 2: 2)
- We Japanese, Volume II. Yokohama, Japan: Yamagata Press, 1937 June (Box-folder 2: 3)
- Photographs of the whale hunting trip "Nisshin Maru No. 1 Expedition" and photograph booklet titled In Commemoration of the Visit of Foreign Commercial Representatives to Japan, 1948-1949 (Box-folder 2: 4)
- Osaka police force press release and accompanying photographs, 1950 (Box-folder 2: 5)
- Photographs, 1950 (Box-folder 2: 6)
  Includes subjects such as the Korean conflict, Inchon, MacArthur, refugees, Japanese police, and Japanese education.
- Photographs of Japanese women pertaining to the "Kimono Revolt" article, 1947-1949 (Box-folder 2: 7)
- Army photographs of Japan, 1940s (Box-folder 2: 8)
- Army photographs and Associated Press wire photos, 1941-1943 (Box-folder 2: 9)
- Panoramic photographs of rooftops, undated (Box-folder 2: 10)
- Photographs from Japan, circa 1948 (Box-folder 2: 11)
  Includes undated images of an old woman and her grandson, an old Japanese woman laughing, and Ken and Marjorie Kantor in front of Radio Tokyo in 1948.
- NBC photographs, 1946-1953 (Box-folder 2: 12)
- Photograph of Kantor on Bob Hope's tour of the Far East, 1957 (Box-folder 2: 13)
- NBC photographs of Bob Hope and Ken Kantor, 1957 (Box-folder 2: 14)
- Autographed photograph of Ken and Marjorie Kantor with Bob Hope, 1957 (Box-folder 2: 15)
- Identification cards of Ken and Marjorie Kantor, 1946-1948 (Box-folder 3: 1)
- Book of phone numbers, undated (Box-folder 3: 2)
- Correspondence to family in California from Kantor in Japan, 1948-1950 (Box-folder 3: 3)
- Correspondence to Marjorie Kantor from Japanese individuals after she was interviewed by radio's "Uncle Come-Come" in Tokyo, 1950 (Box-folder 3: 4)
- Correspondence from Kantor's travel from Tokyo to Los Angeles, 1949 (Box-folder 3: 5)
- "Tattoo for a Warrior," Life Magazine, Vol. 30, No. 17, 1951 April 23 (Box-folder 3: 6)
- "Climbing Mount Fujiyama," Travel Magazine, 1950 February (Box-folder 3: 7)
- News clippings, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 3: 8)
  From Cairo and Alexandria-based American newspapers and Cairo-based newspapers with American news.
- Pacific Stars and Stripes: Christmas Edition, for American Forces in Japan and Korea, 1946 December 25 (Box-folder 3: 9)
- Pacific Stars and Stripes: The First Year, for American Forces in Japan and Korea, 1946 September 2 (Box-folder 3: 10)
- Best Ukiyoe Prints, slide film collection, undated (Box 4)
  Includes 5 sets of 15 slides: (A) Hiroshige, (B) Utamaro, (C) Hokusai, (E) Kiyonga, (F) Sharaku.
- Slides found in the rubble of Pyongyang, 1950 (Box 4)
- Memorabilia, undated
  - Korean passport (Box 4)
  - Dog tag for Marjorie A. Crook (Box 4)
  - Flags of Korea, Japan, and Pakistan (Box 5)
  - Maps of Tokyo, Japan, Asia, and the world (Box 5)